( ROLLING THUNDER )
What 's that ambulance doing out there ?
I don 't know . I 'll check it out .
- Evening , sir . - How 's it going , Griff ?
I can 't complain ... and won 't .
- Is that him ? - Yep , might just be some crackpot ,
but I figured I should call you anyway .
Did he ask for me by name ?
Nope , asked for the agent in charge of the God 's Hand case .
Said he had some important info .
Didn 't say what ?
Nope , said he 'd only talk to you .
You the agent in charge of the God 's Hand case ?
That 's right . Wesley Doyle .
That 's a picture of you and your mother , huh ?
I 'd appreciate it if you wouldn 't take things off of my desk .
Sorry about that . Guess I 've been in here awhile .
I 've already had a look at all your plaques and your citations .
Didn 't really care to have a look at those .
So ...
what can I do for you , Mister ...
Meiks . Name 's Fenton Meiks .
Listen , this may sound a little bit crazy , but ...
I know who the God 's Hand Killer is .
All right , I 'll bite .
Who ?
You haven 't even heard me out yet
and already you doubt me .
Why is that ?
( CHUCKLES )
Because in a case like this , nobody just walks into the office
and tells you who the killer is . It just doesn 't happen that way .
Sometimes truth defies reason , Agent Doyle .
Yeah ? Who is it then ?
My brother .
What makes you think that ?
I got a call from him ...
last night .
( PHONE RINGS )
Hello ?
- Hello ? - Demons are taking over the world !
Adam ?
I can 't destroy them all .
They 're everywhere . I can 't take it anymore .
Let 's talk about this , Adam .
There 's nothing to talk about !
It 's over . Whatever happens ...
You have to take me to the rose garden .
You promised , remember ?
- That 's just till ... - Remember ?
- Adam ? - You promised !
( PHONE CLICKS , DIAL TONE )
â  ª There 'll be peace â  ª
â  ª In the valley â  ª
â  ª For me â  ª
â  ª Some sweet , sweet day. â  ª
( GUN FIRES )
( ROLLING THUNDER )
Meat ?
That 's where all this took place .
It 's about 200 miles west of here , just north of Abilene .
Why 'd you go to Thurman ?
To bury Adam ... In the rose garden .
Why would you do that ?
I promised him I would .
A long time ago .
That 's a pretty wild story , Mr. Meiks .
I don 't see what , if anything , this has got to do with my case .
Adam is the God 's Hand Killer , Agent Doyle .
He 's the one you 're looking for .
Did he tell you that before he ...
Asked you to take him to Thurman ?
If that 's the case , you left that part out .
I haven 't finished yet .
- Oh , there 's more ? - A lot more .
Excuse me a minute .
( PHONE RINGS )
( RINGS )
Meat sheriff 's office .
Can I talk to a sheriff there , please ?
This is Agent Wesley Doyle of the FBI .
He 's not in right now . May I help you ?
I 've got a man here in my office name of Fenton Meiks .
Fenton Meiks ?
What 's he doing there ?
You know him ?
Well , yeah . He caused a bit of a ruckus here earlier .
He stole an ambulance and his brother 's body too .
Did my story check out ?
Yeah , it did .
So am I under arrest now ?
( CHUCKLES )
You damn sure should be .
Apparently the sheriff there is willing to forgive and forget
just as long as you 'll bring that ambulance back .
Nobody wants to press any charges .
You gotta love small towns .
Why would you go to all that trouble
just to walk in here and confess it to me ?
I 'm here because I can 't live with what I know anymore .
What exactly do you know ?
That is your mother , isn 't it ?
- Yeah , it is . - I knew it .
You got the same eyes .
Why don 't we get back to your story ?
What makes you think that your brother 's the God 's Hand Killer ?
I know it was him .
How do you know ?
It started back in Thurman .
It was near the summer of 1979 .
â  ª I got the joy , joy , joy , joy â  ª
â  ª Down in my heart ... â  ª
You 're supposed to say " Where ? "
I don 't want to sing that dumb song .
You don 't have to sing it . Just say , " Where ? "
All right . Where ?
Not now . I 'll point to you when it 's time .
â  ª I got the joy , joy , joy , joy â  ª
â  ª Down in my heart â  ª
- Where ? - â  ª Down in my heart â  ª
â  ª I got the joy , joy , joy , joy down in my heart â  ª
â  ª To stay â  ª
â  ª And if the devil doesn 't like it he can sit on a tack â  ª
- Ouch . - â  ª Sit on a tack â  ª
â  ª To stay. â  ª
Who was that chick who threw up ?
Oh , that was Katie Hagen . She is sure pretty though .
- It was real messy though . - Oh yeah .
All over the floor .
And when the principal fell ...
( LAUGHING )
â  ª I got the joy , joy , joy ... â  ª
FENTON 'S VOICE : We lived right behind the Thurman Public Rose Garden .
In the house where they used to keep the gardeners back in the ' 50s .
Dad had gotten a good deal on it
back when he and mom got married .
â  ª ... Down in my heart to stay. â  ª
TV narrator : The unexpected incident
that creates those dangerous moments .
The ropes were suddenly off the alligator .
FENTON 'S VOICE : Adam was three years younger than me .
Our mom had died giving birth to him ,
so I basically took care of him
ever since I can remember .
Our dad worked as a mechanic over in Jupiter .
He usually got home around 5 : 30
and we 'd all have dinner together .
- Hey , kiddos . - ADAM : Hey , Dad .
Something sure smells good .
- How was your day ? - FENTON : It was all right .
Let 's eat .
DAD : Whoa there , tiger . Save some for us .
- I sure love peas . - You must .
You better be careful though . You might turn into one .
Say , how 'd you do on that math test ?
Barely passed .
I was never any good at math either .
Shoot , I still can 't do anything without a calculator .
But there 's going to be another test next week .
That one 's going to be even harder .
Hey , don 't sound so glum .
Tell you what ,
we 'll sit down this weekend ,
see if we can 't figure out that junk together , okay ?
All right .
Hey , Fenton ,
can we go and see " Meatballs " after school tomorrow ?
We 've already seen it .
I want to see it again .
We 're gonna go see " The Warriors . "
We can 't . It 's rated R.
We 'll sneak in .
Teeth all brushed ?
You sure about that , Adam ?
All right , breath test time .
- Dad ! - ( LAUGHING )
- I did brush them . - I 'm just yoking with you , egghead .
Don 't worry , Fenton , I know you 're too big for a good night kiss .
Night , boys , sleep tight .
Don 't let those bedbugs bite .
That 's right . Love you guys .
- ADAM : Love you too , Dad . - Night , Dad .
Good night , Curtis .
I want to see " Meatballs " again .
Fine , you can see " Meatballs , "
and I 'll see " The Warriors . "
But I don 't like to watch movies by myself .
Too bad .
Please ?
Fine . Fine , just go to bed .
Fenton 's voice : That was our family .
Just the three of us .
All of Mom and Dad 's relatives had died off
so there was no one left but us .
We didn 't mind though .
We didn 't need anybody else .
We were happy together .
Until ...
- Fenton ! Wake up . - ADAM : Dad ?
Adam , get up . I 've got something to tell you .
- Dad , what 's wrong ? - It 's okay .
Adam , wake up and listen .
I need you both to listen to me very carefully .
Something 's happened .
FENTON 'S VOICE : He said he 'd had a vision that night .
A vision from God .
( BASEBALL GAME ON RADIO )
An angel came to him and told him the truth of this world .
And revealed God 's special purpose ...
For our family .
The end of the world is coming . It 's near .
The angel showed me .
There are demons among us .
The devil has released them for the final battle .
It 's being fought ... right now .
But nobody knows it , except us ,
and others like us .
I 'm scared , Dad .
There 's nothing to be afraid of , tiger .
We 've been chosen by God . He will protect us .
He 's given us special jobs to do .
We don 't fear these demons . We destroy them .
We pick them up , one by one ,
and we pitch them out of this world .
That 's God 's purpose for us .
The angel called us God 's Hands .
So we 're like superheroes ?
That 's right .
We 're a family of superheroes
that are going to help save the world .
But , Dad , that doesn 't make any sense .
I know it sounds that way , son ,
but it 's the truth .
So , what are our superpowers ?
Well ...
we can see the demons ,
while other people can 't .
And the angel told me that God would be sending us
three weapons to destroy them with .
Magical weapons ?
I imagine so .
When do we get ' em ?
I don 't know , the angel just said soon .
That 's all I was told , except that ...
We 're not supposed to tell anybody about any of this !
Absolutely no one .
If we do ...
we put them and ourselves in danger .
Fenton ?
Don 't worry . It 's okay .
It 's a lot to understand .
I wanted to wait to tell you
until I had a chance to figure it out myself .
But the angel said I had to do it now .
Fenton ?
FENTON 'S VOICE : I didn 't know what to say or how to feel .
Do you understand what I told you ?
The Judgment Day 's here .
It was too messed up to understand
or even acknowledge .
Soon we 'll all be in Heaven .
You , me , Adam , with Mommy .
I didn 't realize it at that moment ...
- At least , not consciously ... - She 's waiting to see us in Heaven .
But my happy and mostly secure world had just been flipped over
and there were dark things under there .
- Judgment Day is here . - Very dark things .
We 've been chosen by God .
And my little boy 's mind just couldn 't take it .
DAD : Adam ! Fenton !
Up and at ' em , boys !
Morning , kiddo . Come on , lazybones .
It 's late , we overslept .
Let 's go ! Snap to it and get dressed . I 've got to get to work .
I 'll drop you guys off on the way .
What 's wrong with you ?
Nothing .
Radio : â  ª She still blames me ... â  ª
Let me have a bite of that .
â  ª Her dreams are gone. â  ª
Fenton 's voice : None of us mentioned it .
It was only a dream ... A nightmare .
Nothing that crazy could be real .
Everything was okay , just like before .
Have a good day at school , boys .
And remember not to tell anyone what I told you last night !
We won 't Dad , bye !
( SCHOOL BELL RINGS )
TEACHER : I want you all to copy down this sentence .
We 're going to go through the structure . " The girl ... "
" in ... the blue dress ... "
Fenton 's voice : I refused to believe it .
That whole next week was just a dream too .
TEACHER : " walked her ... "
brown dog . "
Like when Dad started bringing home
the magical weapons .
He was on his way to work ...
When God called to him .
( COUNTRY MUSIC ON RADIO )
DAD : Hold this , be careful .
I still can 't understand what these gloves are for , though .
Fenton 's voice : Just a long , long dream .
TEACHER : Write this down in big letters ...
DAD : Boys ! Boys !
Look at this .
We 've got them all .
It won 't be long now .
The angel came again last night and told me that .
God will be sending us a list of the first seven demons soon .
Fenton 's voice : It wasn 't real . It couldn 't be .
I just had to wait it out .
Come over here a minute , Fenton .
- I 'm washing dishes . - They can wait .
Come here . I want to talk to you .
I know you 've had some trouble ...
Adjusting to everything that 's happened this week .
I 'm sorry .
But God has willed this and we must obey God .
Maybe you just dreamed it .
I didn 't dream it .
I wouldn 't make up something like that , son .
Maybe ...
May ... maybe you 're not right in the head .
It happened , Fenton .
It 's true .
You 'll see that soon .
That 's what I wanted to talk to you about .
I got the first list .
FENTON 'S VOICE : The angel came to him while he was at work .
( FIRE CRACKLING )
( SANDER GRINDING )
( PA ANNOUNCEMENTS )
( FLAMES ROARING )
Dad ...
these are people 's names .
That 's right .
And they 'll look like people too .
But they 're not .
The angel said when I lay my hands on them ,
I 'll reveal them for what they truly are .
That 's what the gloves are for .
I get them and bring them back here with the gloves on ,
and once they 're back here , I take the gloves off and reveal them .
You 'll see , then you 'll believe .
TEACHER : Does anyone know what this word means ?
FENTON 'S VOICE : The dream had finally ended .
It was all real .
( YELLS )
And I had to stop him .
The obvious answer was to tell somebody what he was planning .
But I couldn 't do that .
I loved him , even if he had gone crazy .
Dad , look , I got a list too .
Where 'd you get this , Adam ?
God gave it to me .
Isn 't Travis Shed that boy who was picking on you last week ?
He 's a demon .
Tell the truth , Adam .
You made this list up yourself , didn 't you ?
- No , God did . - Adam .
Come on , right here .
Listen to me , son ,
you can 't just make stuff like that up .
We destroy demons .
If we were to use your list , we wouldn 't be destroying demons ,
we 'd be killing people .
And we can never do that .
Destroying demons is a good thing .
Killing people is bad . Do you understand ?
- I 'm sorry , Dad . - That 's all right .
It 's okay . You 've just got to have a little patience .
Don 't worry , God will send you your own list when you 're older .
Okay , go do some homework .
FENTON 'S VOICE : The only thing left to do was to tell .
That was easier said than done .
Dad had promised to take us to the movies that night .
But he didn 't come home from work .
When 's Dad coming home ?
I don 't know .
Think he 's destroying a demon ?
- It 's all make-believe , Adam . - No , it 's not , it 's true !
Listen to me , none of that demon junk is real .
Daddy ... he just made it up .
- No , he didn 't . - He did too .
Just like Santa Claus .
You remember last Christmas when you caught Dad
putting our presents under the tree , don 't you ?
It 's just like that .
Adam , have I ever lied to you ?
All right , look , Dad made up this whole thing .
Those names on Dad 's list are real people .
Do you understand ?
But , why would he make it up ?
I don 't know .
I think we should leave .
You mean ... run away ?
Will you go with me ? Only for a little while .
I don 't want to leave Dad .
Neither do I.
But we might have to .
Why ?
Dad 's gonna kill somebody .
( CAR APPROACHING )
( ENGINE STOPS , DOOR SHUTS )
Son , come over here .
- ( MUFFLED CRIES ) - Come on , I need your help .
ADAM : Dad ?
Come on out here , Adam .
Shine that light over here .
( STRIKES MATCH )
ADAM : Hey , Dad , who is that ?
That 's a demon , son .
Come on in here , boys . It 's all right .
Go on , don 't be afraid .
FENTON 'S VOICE : God came to him earlier that day
and told him that the time had come .
After work , he drove down to Jacksonville ,
about 45 minutes or so southwest of Thurman .
He said he 'd never been there before ,
but he had no problem finding it .
God was leading him .
- Cynthia Harbridge ? - Yes ?
Dad , don 't . Please don 't .
Fenton , if I could spare you this , I would .
But we are God 's servants ,
and his will must be served .
Don 't be afraid , son .
( MUFFLED CRIES )
( ROLLING THUNDER )
Is that true ?
Why would I make it up ?
Where 's your father now ?
Dead .
Sir , I was thinking about heading out .
Unless you need me to stay .
No ...
that 's all right . You go ahead .
Have a good night , sir .
So he killed that woman right there in front of you ?
Maybe not to his way of thinking .
See , to him , he hadn 't killed a woman ,
he had destroyed a demon .
He believed that when he laid his hands on her ,
it revealed her sins .
( SCREAMS )
( GASPS )
( PANTING )
FENTON : Dad , don 't , please !
( CRICKETS CHIRPING )
( FENTON CRYING )
DAD : No , Adam .
Do it like this .
It 's got to be done a certain way .
The angel was real specific .
ADAM : Why out here in the rose garden ?
God chose it .
Just like he chose us , I suppose .
Don 't cry for her , Fenton .
She wasn 't human .
Didn 't you see that when I touched her ?
- ( SNIFFS ) - ADAM : I saw it , Dad .
You killed her .
I didn 't kill her , son .
I destroyed her . She was a demon .
I wasn 't so sure I could do it , myself .
I mean , she looked like a woman to me too .
But after I touched her ...
All I could see was the evil ,
and I had to do it .
I 'm sorry you didn 't see it too .
You will next time .
You ... you 're going to do it again ?
This is our job now , son .
- You 've got to accept that . - I won 't let you .
You can 't stop it . We are doing God 's ...
I 'll tell .
If you do , someone will die .
The angel was clear on that . Do you understand ?
Answer me , Fenton , do you understand ?
DOYLE : So you didn 't tell ?
Naw , I should have , but I was afraid .
I loved my father , but I was terrified of him .
So now you understand why I know
my brother 's the God 's hand killer ?
Have you got any physical proof ?
I read in the paper ...
that only one of the bodies of the six victims
had been found . Is that true ?
You read it in the paper , didn 't you ?
That doesn 't necessarily mean it 's true .
Well , in this case it does .
See , the first victim was found ... mutilated .
With a note saying that God 's hand had taken him .
All the rest , only notes were found , no bodies .
How do you know they 're dead ?
We don 't , for sure .
But the first note told us
we wouldn 't find any more bodies from then on .
Said ... he wanted to keep ' em .
I got a pretty good idea where the rest of them bodies are .
The rose garden .
Why didn 't you tell me that in the first place ?
Would you believe me ?
Come on .
Here .
What 's this ?
Put ' em on .
Or I 'll put them on for you .
Let 's go .
I got it .
So tell me something ...
Why didn 't you come see me sooner ?
You 're going to want to get on I-30 east up here .
I just can 't imagine how you can
keep something like that inside for so long .
I guess I avoided it .
' Cause I wanted to .
You never did tell me why it is you keep
just that one picture of your mother in your office .
( SIGHS )
My mother was murdered
a couple of days after that picture was taken .
Butchered by some whacked out killer like your Dad .
Did they ever catch him ?
No .
Is that why you took this job ?
( CHUCKLES ) You 're pretty good at this .
You ever think about becoming a cop ?
You know , when I was a kid .
Well , you got the instincts for it .
A cop 's gotta have good instincts .
You know what mine are telling me now ?
You are hiding something from me .
What is it you think I 'm hiding ?
Why don 't you just keep talking and maybe I 'll figure that out ?
TV : You okay , Dad ?
I 'm all right , son .
Here I come .
Dad , why did God let this happen to me ?
Don 't blame God , Davy , it wasn 't his fault .
God let me do it .
What God lets you do is decide for yourself what you will do .
You 're not a puppet with strings tied to you .
- No . - So God doesn 't make you do anything .
He wants you to decide for yourself .
FENTON 'S VOICE : After that night nothing much happened .
Dad didn 't mention it anymore .
Neither did Adam .
Once a full month had gone by ,
I completely convinced myself it was over ,
and everything was going to be all right .
- Bye . - See y 'all later .
You see " Dukes of Hazard " last night ?
- Mm-hmm . - Remember when Daisy Duke bent over ?
I like Boss Hogg . He 's funny .
Man , I 'd do anything to really see her tits .
- Ohh , you said " tit " ... - Shut up , Adam .
You want to spend the night tonight ?
- We can wrap Corey 's house . - Sure , I 'm gonna have to ask my dad .
My mom can call and ask if you want .
- Sure . - I 'll see you in a little bit .
- Bye . - Hey , what 's wrap mean ?
Tell you later . Come on , race you !
Come on .
Naw , I 'm gonna go around on the road .
- ADAM : Dad ? - In here .
Who 's van is that out there ?
Ours . Isn 't she a beaut ?
Your friend 's mom just called .
I told her not tonight .
We got some work to do in the morning .
FENTON 'S VOICE : Dad told us that there were moments in everyone 's life
when they could just suddenly disappear
without anyone knowing where they went or why .
He said those were the moments when .
God 's hands could reach out and take you .
According to Dad , nothing ,
not even a camera , could catch us .
We were invisible when we were God 's hands .
ADAM : What do we do now , Dad ?
We wait . We 'll get him when comes out , just like I told you , remember ?
Fenton ?
I can 't do this , Dad .
" Can 't " never could do anything .
- I can do it , Dad . - You sure can , tiger .
What if someone sees us ?
- They won 't . - It 's broad daylight !
I told you , God will blind them for us .
There he is , boys .
- Come on , Fenton . - Dad , I can 't .
Yes , you can . Now move !
Do what I tell you !
FENTON : Please , Trixie .
Trixie , come on .
Come , Trixie . Trixie ... come on .
Whatcha doin ' , boy ?
( SOBBING ) My dog , she 's ...
She 's under your car .
Oh , well , let 's see .
Help me grab his legs .
Help me grab his legs ! Now !
Come on !
- DAD : Edward March ? - ( GRUNTS )
You think that 's an innocent man there , don 't you ?
Well , it 's not .
You didn 't think anyone knew about that , did you ?
- But God saw you ! - Dad , don 't , please ! Quiet .
And you can 't escape God 's wrath .
( DIGGING )
I can 't believe you still didn 't see it .
He was a murderer of little children , Fenton .
Babies .
He 's the murderer .
We 've got to get out of here , Adam .
- What do you mean ? - We 've got to run away .
I told you we might have to .
I don 't wanna run away .
We have to .
Why ?
Listen to me , Adam .
Dad kills people .
No , he doesn 't . He 's a demon slayer .
That 's all lies , Adam .
No , it 's not . I see it when he touches them .
No , you don 't ! Dad 's brainwashed you .
It 's all a big lie .
He 's a murderer and you help him .
Nah-uh ! We 're just serving God 's will .
- I 'm telling Dad on you ! - Adam ! Adam ...
Adam !
Get up and get dressed .
And don 't wake your brother .
Sit down .
Your brother told me what you said last night .
I want you to know I 've never killed anything in my whole life .
That 's a lie and you know it .
I did a lot of thinking and praying after you went to bed .
I asked the angel to visit you .
Instead he visited me .
And he told me something ...
I don 't want to believe .
What ?
It doesn 't matter .
Because together you and I are going to prove him wrong .
You just don 't have any faith .
That 's why you can 't see the truth .
But we 're going to change that .
I want you to dig a hole right here .
Need to be about 10 ' deep ,
and 15 ' wide on both sides .
The length and the width should form a perfect square .
- What ? - You heard me .
Why ?
' Cause I 'm your father and you 'll do what I tell you .
You understand ?
Do ya ?
- Yes , sir . - All right , then .
I expect half that to be dug
by the time I get home from work tonight .
- Dad , I can 't do that . - Pray !
FENTON 'S VOICE : I started digging that goddamn hole ,
but I did not pray . I would not .
I hated God . I despised him .
My hatred helped me dig .
Kept me going .
Dad 's or God 's or the angel 's ,
or whoever 's plan it was , would not work on me .
ADAM : Hey , Fenton !
I knew what Dad was doing was wrong ,
and nothing was going to change that .
Fenton ?
I 'm sorry I told on you .
You didn 't tell him what I said about running away , did you ?
- No . - Will you go with me then ?
- There 's no reason to go . - He 's a killer .
No , he 's not .
I 've been praying for you .
- Have you been praying ... - Nope , and I 'm not going to !
- Dad said ... - I don 't care what Dad said .
He might be able to make me dig this stupid hole ,
but he can 't make me pray .
Just get out of here and leave me alone .
I 'll help if you promise you won 't tell Dad .
I don 't want your help .
But there 's another shovel in the shed .
- Get out of here ! - Butthole !
FENTON 'S VOICE : I wanted to run away ... far away ,
but I still couldn 't leave Adam , no matter how crazy Dad was turning .
Besides ...
there was nowhere to go .
( ADAM GIGGLING )
Finally gave up , huh , kiddo ?
I didn 't give up .
I 'll be out there again in the morning .
Hey , come on , I didn 't mean it like that .
I don 't want to fight with you , son .
I 'm not doing this to hurt you .
Wish you could understand that .
- What 's the matter with you ? - Nothing .
- Let me see your hands . - They 're fine . Let me see them .
Didn 't you wear gloves today ?
I didn 't need them . I 'm fine .
Here .
Help ease the pain .
I said I was fine .
Fenton , I know you 're mad at me , but that 's no reason
to cause yourself pain . Now you take those .
I got an extra pair of work gloves in the shed .
I want you to use those from now on .
It won 't do you any good now you 've wrecked your hands ,
but a couple days and you 'll be fine .
I want you to know I 'm proud of you .
And I know God 's proud of you too .
Take some time off and let those blisters callous over .
Then you can get back to it , all right ?
Well , good night then .
Come on , tiger , bedtime .
ADAM : Fenton gets to stay up . Please , Dad ?
DAD : Come on .
Brush your teeth , I 'll be in to say good night in a minute .
FENTON 'S VOICE : I kept digging .
My hand 's bled but I wouldn 't stop .
I kept at it morning , noon and night for five days .
And by the sixth day , that hole was as dark and deep
as my hatred for Dad 's god .
Well , you finished it all right .
I bet you didn 't pray once the whole time , did you ?
Nope .
FENTON 'S VOICE : We started the cellar after that .
At least , that 's what Dad called it .
But I knew better .
We were building a dungeon down there .
We basically built a big , wooden box in the ground .
DAD : Good , boys , get it over there . Cover it good .
Fenton 's voice : Dad said it would hold .
He said God would see to it .
DAD : Adam ! Get back here and help me push !
Come on ! Keep it going ! Push it !
Go ! Go ! Keep it moving .
Keep it moving !
( GRUNTING )
You boys did good . Especially you , Fenton .
I just did as I was told .
Well , let 's give this a try . What do you think ?
All right .
FENTON 'S VOICE : The next night he brought home another demon .
Get down here .
DAD : It has to be done . It 's God 's will .
C 'mon , do it like I showed you . The neck first .
( MUFFLED CRIES )
Fenton !
Fenton , get back here !
Boy !
Fenton !
Fenton 's voice : I half expected angels
or even God himself to come out of the night and stop me .
But I had to do it .
It had to end .
- Hello ? - RADIO : 10-34 to any and all units
in the vicinity of Garden . We have complaints of a 501 ,
driving on the alternate side of the street ...
Hello ?
Hello !
( DOG BARKING )
Take it easy , boy .
Don 't break my door down .
What 's your problem ?
Craziest thing I 've heard in a long time .
- What are you doing ? - Calling your dad .
- You can 't ! - Yes , I can .
You ought to be ashamed making up stories like that .
But ... but it 's true ! I can show you !
Come on . Let 's go .
All right , it 's around back , under the shed .
That 's enough of that now , boy .
I 'll put an end to this . Come on .
N-N-No , I don 't think you understand . He 's around back .
See what your Dad 's got to say about all this .
What 's the trouble , Sheriff ?
Sorry to wake you , but your boy here seems to have a problem .
Well , come on in .
SHERIFF : I was about to lock up , head over to Lake Thompson .
You know , get a jump on those bass .
And he comes running in with this wild story .
Yep , it 's quite a tale , all right .
It 's the truth and you know it .
It makes me crazy to think that he ...
Told everyone down at your office too .
You can set your mind at ease about that .
I was the only one there .
' Course I don 't believe a word of it .
What does get me though is why
would he make up such a crazy story ?
I don 't know why he made it up .
Probably did it to get back at me
for punishing him earlier .
Did you tell him about that ?
He 's lying . Just check the shed .
I don 't know what to do with him .
Well , they hit puberty ,
seem to lose all respect for ya .
Me and my boys survived it , you will too .
Just check the shed ... Or the rose garden .
I-I-I could show you where they 're buried .
Boy , why don 't you just quit all this nonsense ?
Please , I can show you .
Maybe we ought to check the shed , just to ...
quiet him down .
If it has to be done ,
it has to be done .
What do you think , kiddo ?
Does it have to be done ?
FENTON : See ?
I figured we ought to have a storm cellar .
Go on down and check it out .
Just watch your step , I 'm not much of a carpenter .
I don 't see a thing .
He was here .
Boy ... do you realize
how much trouble you could get into over a thing like this ?
They must have moved him because he was here .
Adam ! Adam 's got him somewhere , I know it .
I think I 've seen enough .
But ...
I can show you where the bodies are buried .
Please , you 've got to believe me !
- ( AX THUDS ) - ( SHERIFF GRUNTS )
( GASPS )
May God welcome you .
And keep you .
( VOMITING )
( PLASTIC RUSTLES )
I never killed a man before tonight .
I 've seen you kill plenty .
Those were demons !
That was a man . Why can 't you see that ?
- You didn 't have to kill him . - I had to protect our mission .
There is no mission !
That man is dead because of you !
You see him ? Look at him !
He 's dead because you have no faith .
Do you understand what you made me do ?
- You made me commit murder ! - I didn 't make you do anything !
- You did ! You 're crazy ! - ( YELLS )
ADAM : Dad , no !
Dad , don 't !
( DAD GROANS )
( DAD CRYING )
It 's all right , Dad .
Don 't cry .
Wait a minute , Fenton .
Go on inside , son .
I 'll be there in a minute to tuck you in .
Go on , it 's all right .
Go .
Come into the shed .
Come in and shut the door .
Are you afraid ?
- Of what ? - Y-you .
Only demons should fear me .
You 're not a demon , are you ?
The angel said you were .
I can 't believe that .
I won 't .
You 're my son .
I love you more than my own life .
You know what 's funny about all this , Fenton ?
I 'm afraid of you .
( WHIMPERS )
Go on .
- But , Dad ... - Go on , get down there .
I don 't want to do this , Fenton , but I have to .
I had to kill a man tonight .
I can 't let that happen again .
But , Dad , I promise I won 't tell .
I can 't trust you !
I wish I could .
- Now , go on . - But , Dad ... I 'm sorry .
I 'm sorry , too , Fenton ,
but this has to be done .
Now , you get on down there ,
or I 'll put you down there myself .
- But , Dad ... - Go !
No ...
No ! No !
- No ... - ( GRUNTING )
Dad , please , Dad , Dad ...
No , please , no !
Please , Dad ...
You 'll stay down here until you see the truth .
Please ! Dad , no !
- Please ! - Pray to God , Fenton .
- Dad , no ! Please ! - Pray for a vision .
- No ! No ! - Only he can help you now .
Please , don 't do this , Dad .
Please ! Please ! It 's me , Fenton !
Please don 't do this !
It 's me !
I 'm not a demon , please !
Please , it 's me !
Please , don 't do this .
No ! Don 't !
( SHED DOOR OPENS , SHUTS )
( DOOR OPENS )
Fenton ?
Fenton , you all right ?
Adam ?
Adam , is that you ?
Adam .
Adam , you got to get me out of here .
- I can 't . - But I 'm hungry .
And I gotta go to the bathroom .
Dad won 't let me feed you .
I brought you some water though .
He says you can have a cup a day ...
But I 'll bring you more if I can .
Look , Adam , he 's gonna kill me .
You 've got to get me out of here .
I can 't . Put your mouth to the knothole right here .
- You ready ? - Uh-huh .
Here .
You want some more or you want me to save it for later ?
More . More !
You 've got to get me out of here , Adam .
Dad says you 'll probably be out of there by the end of the week .
You just have to accept God 's will .
A week ? I can 't stay in here that long .
I 'll pray for you .
Adam ... ?
- Adam ! - ( DOOR SHUTS )
( POUNDING )
( SCREAMING )
Adam ?
Fenton 's voice : The days came and went .
I counted them by the cracks of light through the hatch door ,
and Adam 's visits with the water .
I only slept when I passed out from exhaustion .
DOYLE : What about your Dad ?
Didn 't he ever come back to at least check on you ?
On the seventh day .
( HATCH OPENING )
Has God spoken to you yet ?
There is no God .
FENTON 'S VOICE : I lost count of the days after that .
It felt like weeks .
I finally went beyond fear
into total insanity .
I saw God .
He had finally sent me a vision .
It was then that I understood my destiny ,
just like Dad said I would .
ADAM : Dad , Fenton 's not answering .
( DOOR OPENS )
DAD : Fenton ?
Fenton !
( NAILS SQUEAKING )
Fenton .
Fenton ?
Come on , kiddo .
Get me that water .
( FENTON WHIMPERING )
Easy , boy . Easy , easy .
Here you go , kiddo .
There you go , buddy .
Dad ?
I saw God .
Just try to take a little sip .
Hey , slow down there .
If you eat too fast , you 'll make yourself sick .
ADAM : So did God tell you about the demons ?
Sorry I ever doubted you , Dad .
I 'm sorry too , son .
What did God look like ?
Kinda hard to describe .
- Was he big ? - Adam .
Let your brother eat in peace .
He can 't explain something like that .
But I want to know .
- Then maybe you should pray for it . - It 's not fair !
All I 've seen are demons and he gets to see God .
That 's right .
But look at the price he paid .
That 's all behind us now .
It 's a new day . Isn 't it , Fenton ?
Mm-hmm .
- We 're gonna go get us a demon now ? - After a while .
When Fenton 's ready .
FENTON 'S VOICE : A week later , I was ready .
My first demon was to be Brad White from Dallas .
- FENTON : There it is . - DAD : I see it .
You sure you 're ready for this ?
Yes , sir .
I bought these for you .
You 'll need them now that God has spoken to you .
- All right , let 's go . - ADAM : I want to go too , Dad .
Not this time , Adam .
You stay here and keep your eyes peeled .
Don 't worry , your time will come .
Let 's go .
( DOG BARKING )
Hey .
- Sorry to bother you . - Yeah .
My son and I , we had a flat on our van .
Huh , yeah ?
I was wondering if you had a tire iron , we left ours at home .
Hey , pal , what 's with the gloves ?
Oh , uh ... to change the tire .
- Don 't want to get your hands dirty . - Yeah .
WOMAN : Brad , who is it ?
Mind your business , you fucking bitch !
Goddamn women .
( CHUCKLES )
Yeah , I think I got one for you .
- Out back . - Great .
Back here .
Let 's see .
( TOOLS CLATTER )
Here it is .
Shit !
( GROANING )
Grab his legs .
( MATCH STRIKING )
( GROANS )
Brad White ?
You know , Fenton ,
I 've been waiting for this moment ever since all this started .
I 'm ready to fulfill my destiny .
I 'm proud of you , son .
( GRUNTS )
( MUFFLED ) Fuck you !
You fuck !
( MUFFLED )
Destroy him .
ADAM : Dad !
( GURGLING )
Dad , no , no .
( WHISPERING )
ADAM : No ...
( SNIFFING )
( BRAD MUMBLING )
- No ! - ( SCREAMING )
I buried him in the rose garden .
We went to the sheriff 's ...
Office a week later and told him that ...
Dad just didn 't come home one day .
They filed a missing persons ,
but they didn 't find anything .
After a while , they sent us to separate orphanages .
So ...
nobody ever knew about any of this ?
No .
Not until now .
What about Adam , he didn 't tell anybody ?
Listen , you mind if we just sit here awhile ?
I don 't much feel like talking anymore .
Tell me more about that promise you made to your brother .
It was later on that night .
( DIGGING )
( ADAM SOBBING )
Adam ?
If you ever destroy me ,
promise me you 'll bury me here .
I promise to God I 'll bury you here .
DOYLE : I don 't get it .
He promised you that ...
He 'd bury you here ?
Yeah .
If he killed you ?
No , not killed . Destroyed .
Don 't make any sense .
Yes , it does .
If the man standing in front of you is Adam Meiks .
( SCREAMING )
So you killed all those people .
No , no , I told you before ,
I 've never killed anyone in my life .
Fenton was the killer .
Just stop the bullshit and tell me the truth .
You 'll understand soon .
Just let me show you where I buried Fenton .
Hold it !
You take it real slow .
This is it .
This is the spot .
Doyle : There 's too many graves here .
There 's only six victims .
Fenton didn 't bury his victims here .
He kept them as trophies in his basement .
This is where I put demons .
You thought your brother was a demon .
He was .
That 's why he couldn 't see the truth .
Dad knew it too , he just couldn 't accept it .
You see , God asked Dad to destroy his son
much like He asked Abraham to sacrifice his son Isaac .
But Dad couldn 't do it .
And God didn 't take pity on Dad like He did Abraham .
So He handed down the duty to me .
Fenton knew I 'd come sooner or later ,
that 's why he left those notes to lure me in .
I guess he figured that when the killings
made the news I 'd come for him .
But I had to wait until God put him on my list .
To come before that would have been murder .
Radio : â  ª The bear will be gentle â  ª
â  ª And the wolf will be tame â  ª
â  ª And the lion shall lay down with the lamb â  ª
â  ª That 's what he said â  ª
â  ª And the beast from the wild â  ª
â  ª Will be lit by a little child â  ª
â  ª And I will be changed from this creature â  ª
â  ª That I am â  ª
â  ª And there 'll be peace â  ª
â  ª In the valley for me â  ª
- ( TYPING ) - â  ª Someday â  ª
â  ª Peace in the valley â  ª
â  ª For me , dear Lord , I pray â  ª
â  ª There 'll be no sadness â  ª
â  ª No sorrow â  ª
â  ª No trouble I see â  ª
- Adam . - â  ª There 'll be peace â  ª
â  ª In the valley â  ª
â  ª For ... â  ª
â  ª Me. â  ª
Jesus Christ , you really do believe all this stuff .
I 've always believed .
FENTON : That 's all lies , Adam .
ADAM : No , it 's not . I see it when he touches them .
( FENTON SOBBING )
You 're just crazy as hell .
Fenton or Adam or whatever your damn name is .
( SCOFFS )
I don 't really give a fuck .
All I need to know right now ...
Is you are a murdering son of a bitch .
And I got you .
Maybe .
But that 's not going to bring your mother back , is it ?
She 's dead ...
And her killer got away , didn 't he ?
God damn you . Dirty little son of a ...
( SCREAMING )
( GROANING )
DOYLE : How did you know ?
You were on my list .
( GASPING , PANTING )
You didn 't think anybody knew about that , did you ?
God knew .
That 's why He sent me .
( ADAM GRUNTING )
( DOYLE GRUNTS )
I 'm an FBI agent .
They 'll come looking for me .
No , they won 't .
They 'll keep looking for Fenton .
You 're gonna be his last victim .
They 've seen you !
They 'll know it was you .
God will protect me .
( FBI AGENTS TALKING )
That 's right , I want him found and I want him found now !
I can 't right now , I can 't . I 'll get back to you .
- Here . - Thank you .
Are you sure neither one of you can remember what he looks like ?
Look , I told you , it 's just a blur .
I can 't understand that . I looked right at him .
- I shook his hand . - Hey , we 've got a problem .
You 've got to take a look at this .
GRIFF : There he is .
We got you now , buddy .
- ( TAPS MONITOR ) - What is this ?
I can 't explain it ... All the tapes look like this .
- GRIFF : Goddamn it ! - ( BANGS MONITOR )
AGENT 1 : We 're running the name he gave you .
AGENT 2 : It 's got to be a fake name .
AGENT 3 : Sounds fake . Fenton Meiks .
Fenton Meiks ! This is the FBI !
We 're coming in ! Go , go , go !
( HELICOPTER BUZZING )
Clear !
Clear .
- Anything ? - Naw .
All right , let 's dust it .
GRIFF : Oh my God .
There 's no one here , sir .
We found this in the basement .
Is he down there too ?
Not him .
GRIFF : Excuse me .
Didn 't hear you come in . How can I help you ?
I 'm with the FBI . I need to speak to the sheriff , is he in ?
Sure thing . Sheriff ?
Would you like some coffee or something ?
No , I 'm fine , thanks .
- Well , hey , Curtis . - Afternoon , Becky .
- Sheriff ? - Yeah ?
I 'm Agent Griffin Hull of the FBI .
I need to ask you some questions about your brother .
Fenton ?
Yes , sir .
Why don 't you come on around back ?
ADAM : I appreciate you coming by to tell me personally .
I just wanted you to know before we go public .
Listen , if there 's anything I can do , don 't hesitate to call .
I think we got it pretty well covered from here .
But , again , if you think of anything , where he might have gone ,
- or if he contacts you ... - Of course .
All right .
You 're a good man , Agent Hull .
Everything okay , Adam ?
Everything 's just fine , Becky .
God 's will has been served .
BECKY : Praise God .
KID : Wanna race me ?
( DRAMATIC THEME MUSIC PLAYING )